# WENHU CHEN

EL Colegio Rd, Santa Barbara, CA 93106

#### ABOUT ME

I'm a Ph.D. student in Computer Science Department of University of California, Santa Barbara. My research interests lie in natural language processing and machine learning, more specifically, I focus on research topics like machine translation, knowledge base reasoning, semantic parsing and visual captioning.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

# Triangular Architecture for Rare Language Translation

Shuo Ren, Wenhu Chen, Shujie Liu, Mu Li, Ming Zhou and Shuai Ma. Proceedings of ACL 2018, Melbourne, Australia (Oral)

# No Metrics Are Perfect: Adversarial Reward Learning for Visual Storytelling

Wenhu Chen\*, Xin Wang\*, Yuan-Fang Wang and William Yang Wang. Proceedings of ACL 2018, Melbourne, Australia (Oral)

## Variational Knowledge Graph Reasoning

Wenhu Chen, Wenhan Xiong, William Yang Wang, Xifeng Yan. Proceedings of NAACL 2018, New Orleans, CA (Oral)

# Generative Bridging Network in Neural Sequence Prediction

Wenhu Chen, Guanlin Li, Shuo Ren, Shujie Liu, Zhirui Zhang, Mu Li, Ming Zhou. Proceedings of NAACL 2018, New Orleans, CA (Poster)

## Video Captioning via Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning

Xin Wang, Wenhu Chen, Jiawei Wu, Yuan-fang Wang, William Yang Wang. Proceedings of CVPR 2018, Salt Lake City, UTAH

## A Joint Framework for Path Finding and Path Reasoning

Wenhu Chen, William Yang Wang, Xifeng Yan. KBCOM of WSDM 2018, Los Angeles, CA

## Using meta-information in neural machine translation

Evgeny Matusov, Wenhu Chen, Shahram Khadivi. US Patent, 2017

#### Guided alignment training for topic-aware neural machine translation

Wenhu Chen, Evgeny Matusov, Shahram Khadivi, JT Peter. AMTA 2016, Austin, TX (Poster)

#### Facial Emotion Recognition Using PHOG and a Hierarchical Expression Model

Zhao Zhong, Gang Shen, Wenhu Chen. INCos 2013, IEEE

## **SERVICE**

Program Committee in Socal-NLP 2018

Program Committee in EMNLP 2018

Program Committee in AAAI 2019

#### **EDUCATION**

#### University of California, Santa Barbara

Sep 2017-Now

Ph.D in Computer Science

Advisor: Xifeng Yan and William Wang

Overall GPA: 4.0/4.0

## ETH Zurich, Switzerland

Visiting in Computer Science

Overall GPA: 6.0/6.0

June 2016-Dec 2016

RWTH Aachen University, Germany

Sep 2014-Dec 2016

M.S. in Electronics Engineering

Overall GPA: 1.4/1.0

Huazhong University of Science and Technology, China

Sep 2010-June 2014

M.S. in Electronics Engineering

Overall GPA: 86/100

# EXPERIENCE

Microsoft Research Asia

Feb 2017 - Aug 2017

 $Research\ Intern$ 

Beijing, China

- · Designed data-augmentation algorithm for sequence learning
- · Designed new architecture for rare language translation

eBay Research Research Intern December 2015 - June 2016

Aachen, Germany

- · Investigated the usage of statistical alignment in NMT
- · Designed a meta-information based NMT system

Jinyin Dao Inc.

November 2011 - June 2012

Wuhan, China

Designer & Developer

- · Worked on Android Software Development
- · Designed user interface for an Android App

## AWARD

**IDEA Research Grant**: Awarded IDEA research scholarship for exchange program in ETH.

German National Scholarship: Awarded a one-year scholarship sponsored by Robert Bosch Inc.

China Scholarship Committee Scholarship: Awarded full scholarship from CSC for a one-year exchange program in Germany.

MCM Finalist Award: Ranked top 0.5% in The Mathematical Contest in Modeling in 2013.